

avannaldas@hotmail.com (will be shared over email)

Hyderabad, India

abhijitannaldas.com

www.github.com/avannaldas

www.linkedin.com/in/avannaldas in

A Software Engineer and a voracious learner who managed to carve out Data Scientist in himself. Improving expertise day by day through relentless practice and competing in Hackathons. Have extensive experience of building enterprise scale applications in different Microsoft and Open Source technologies.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Instacart Market Basket Analysis [Ranked in top 29%]

Kaggle

08/2017 - 08/2017

 The dataset is a relational set of files describing customers' orders over time. Predict which products will be in a user's next order. Dataset contains a sample of over 3 million grocery orders from more than 200,000 Instacart users [LightGBM, XGBoost, SVC, VotingClassifier, scikit-learn]

Emails Classification

POC

07/2017 - 07/2017

 Classified emails received on mass emails distribution group based on labelled dataset of email subjects.
 [CountVectorizer, TfldfTransformer, SGDClassifier, Pipeline, GridSearchCV, scikit-learn]

Gender Classification [Ranked in top 20%]

In person Hackathon held at Microsoft

06/2017 - 06/2017

 The problem statement was to classify SIFT encoded face images into male and female. [XGBoost]

Quick View

Python Package Index (PyPI)

04/2017 - 04/2017

 Quick View is a visualization package published at Python Package Index. The package plots useful details about pandas dataframe with one line of code. The plots are about categorical variables, null values, unique values, correlation matrix, etc. [pandas, numpy, matplotlib]

Loan Default Prediction [Ranked in top 8%] Hacker Earth

03/2017 - 03/2017

 The problem definition was about credit risk assessment to classify if the loan would be repaid or will default. [XGBoost]

SKILLS

| Machine Learning | | | | |
|----------------------------|--|---|---|--------------|
| Python | | | | lacktriangle |
| SQL Server | | | | 0 |
| Linear Algebra | | | 0 | 0 |
| Calculus | | | 0 | 0 |
| Statistics and Probability | | | 0 | 0 |
| Deep Learning | | | 0 | 0 |
| Hadoop, Spark | | 0 | 0 | 0 |

ACHIEVEMENTS

Stood 3rd among 100 (approx.) participants, in a Security Bug Bash held within the company (2015)

Won Microsoft IT Excellence Award for FY15 Q1, FY15 Q2, FY15 Q3, FY16 Q3

Stood 1st among 200 teams, in an Inter-college programming competition (2011)

Microsoft Student Partner (2010 – 2012)

SOFTWARE ENGINNER @ MICROSOFT IDC

Visual Studio Mobile Center (03/2017 – Present)

Built app distribution capabilities in mobile.azure.com to distribute apps to public stores with Node.js REST APIs and Worker roles.

Enterprise Publishing with HockeyApp (11/2015 – 02/2017)

Enterprise App Publishing within Microsoft. Built custom workflows to extend HockeyApp's distribution capabilities.

Incentives Compensation (03/2015 - 11/2015)

Worked on Microsoft's sellers quota setting and Incentives Compensation (IC). IC helps Microsoft strategically drive sales.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Applications (2009 - 2012)

Sinhgad Institute of Management and Computer Applications, Pune